

IOT DEVELOPER · AI ENTHUSIAST

3-10-20/48/A, Gokhale Nagar, Ramanthapur, Hyderabad, Telangana, 500013, INDIA

🛮 (+91) 9700071361 | 🗖 a.dheeraj.95@gmail.com | 🎁 www.dheeraj.online | 🖸 dheeraj-allamaneni | 🗖 dheerajallamaneni

"Willingness to fail is opportunity to innovate."

Summary

Recent graduate with B.Tech in Electronics and Communication Engineering.Co-Founder & IoT Developer in start-up company ENIGMA Tech. 2 years experience specializing in Robotics, IoT and backend. Interested in devising a better problem-solving strategy for challenging tasks, Machine Learning Dev and love learning new technologies and tools.

Work Experience

ENIGMA Tech.

T.Hub, Hyderabad

CO-FOUNDER & IOT DEVELOPER

Jul. 2015 - PRESENT

Jan. 2015 - Apr. 2015

- Leading a Team of seven, Developed and built intelligent robots and IoT Products.
- Built a Application for Department of Defense Production as part of worlds largest hackathon (SIH-2017), This whole project was demonstrated to Honorable PM Narendra Modi sir and has appreciated for our efforts.

INSIGNIA Labs. Hyderabad, INDIA

RESEARCH INTERN

- Developed long range wireless power transfer system.
- Developed games with Arduino and Raspberry pi.
- Implemented pezio electric power generation.

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

| Jun. 2017 | 1st Place, AngelHack. | Microsoft Campus, India | |
|-----------|--|----------------------------|--|
| Apr. 2017 | Finalist , Smart India Hackathon under Department of Defense Production by Government of India . This whole project was demonstrated to Honorable PM Narendra Modi sir and has appreciated for our efforts. | Bangalore, India | |
| Sep. 2016 | 3rd Place , Megathon (A 24Hrs hackathon) by E-Cell IIT-Hyd and IIIT-Hyd | T.Hub, India | |
| Nov. 2016 | Finalist , Showcased our IoT product Medicine-Remainder to Steve Crocker Chair, ICANN Board of Directors at ICANN57(18th AGM) | Hyderabad, India | |
| Mar. 2016 | 4th Place, International Autonomous Robotics Competition at IIT-Kanpur | Kanpur, India | |
| Dec. 2015 | 2nd Place , International Robotics Competition at IIT-Bombay | Mumbai, India | |
| Oct. 2011 | Distinction , Australian National Chemistry Quiz by ROYAL AUSTRALIAN CHEMICAL INSTITUTE | New Delhi, India | |
| DOMESTIC | | | |

DOMESTIC

| Mar. 2016 1st Place , Autonomous Robotics at JNTUH | India |
|---|-------|
| Mar. 2016 1st Place, Maze Solver (Robotics competition) at CVR College of Engineering | India |
| Apr. 2016 2nd Place , Project expo at Mahatma Gandhi Institute of Technology | India |
| Feb. 2016 1st Place, Robotics Competition Conducted by SAKSHI-ARENAONE Youth-fest | India |
| Feb. 2016 Silver Medal , Best performance in Electronic design projects at Mallareddy college of Engineering | India |
| Jan. 2016 Finalist , DTMF Race at IIT-Hyderabad | India |
| Sep. 2015 1st Place, Robotics Competition at FACEit-2K15(A NATIONAL LEVEL TECHNICAL SYMPOSIUM) | India |
| Jun. 2015 2nd Place , Group Discussion at Anushthana-2K14 (Annual Cultural fest at ACE) | India |
| | |

Presentation

IEEE Paperpresentation at Osmania University

WATER QUALITY MONITORING USING REMOTE SENSING AND NEURAL NETWORKS

Hyderabad, India

Mar. 2015

SWARM ROBOTICS Mar. 2015

Conferences

AWS Cloud Kata for Startups and Developers

Amazon, Hyderabad

ATENDEE

Sep. 2016

enriching talks and interactive panel discussions geared specifically for growing startups, developers & the investor community. Besides providing with the business mentoring, technical training and customer insights, the Cloud Kata session is an excellent opportunity to network with our peers and the AWS team.

CBIT Model United Nations India

DELEGATE OF UGANDA Mar. 2014

• Delegated Human Resource problems of UGANDA to the council.

ACE Model United Nations India

HEAD OF HOSPITALITY AND ORGANIZING COMMITTEE

Jan. 2014

· Organized 3-days MUN Conference.

Technical Skills ___

Programming Languages, : C, MATLAB, Wolfram Mathematica

HDL S,: VHDL, Verilog

Tools Used,: Xilinx ISE, MATLAB R2015a, Mathematica, IBM Bluemix, JSFiddle, NI-LabVIEW and Multisim

Scripting, : Python, JavaScript

Operating Systems, : LINUX, WINDOWS **Markup Languages**, : HTML5, LaTeX

Education

ACE Engineering College

Hyderabad, India

B.Tech. IN Electronics and Communication Engineering

Mar. 2013 - Jun. 2017

- Graduated with "First Class"
- · Major Project: RoadTrack AI based Real time Road quality measurement and mapping with route planning.
- Mini Project: Tracking Beacon Cloud based Real time GPS tracking with Time of Arrival Estimation.

DELTA Junior college Hyderabad, India

INTERMEDIATE EDUCATION IN MATHEMATICS, PHYSICS AND CHEMISTRY

• Percentage: 82.5%

Narayana E-techno School

Hyderabad, India

Secondary Education
• Percentage: **75%**

Certifications

Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms

IIT-Madras Jul. 2014

Digital Circuits and Systems

IIT-Madras Apr. 2015

Machine Learning

STANFORD UNIVERSITY Dec. 2016 - PRESENT

Business Foundations Specialization

WHARTON SCHOOL OF BUSINESS Nov. 2016 - PRESENT

HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web Developers

JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY Feb. 2017 - Apr. 2017